GRAY SANDERS

Lubbock, Texas 79416 • gray.sanders@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/gray-sanders

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced IT Manager with 16 years proven ability to develop IT strategies, policies and procedures. Extensive working experience installing, managing and maintaining Network Systems.

KEY IT QUALIFICATIONS & RESPONSIBILITIES

Databases: SQL, ESRI Enterprise GEO

Platforms: Windows, MAC

Networking: DHCP, DNS servers, Mail server, Fileshare, Unifi Wireless, VoIP, Printers **Operating Systems**: Windows OS; Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2012, 2016 & Hyper-V **Programing Languages**: ASP.net Core, C#, Java, HTML, SQL, PHP, Angular, Visual Basic

Software: Microsoft Exchange; Microsoft Office; Enterprise Content Mgmt. (M-Files); ESRI: Desktop, Server, Portal & Collector

Security: SonicWALL Firewall, SonicWALL Email Security

KEY IT ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Researched, implemented & wrote scripts to insert data from Telemetry device into SQL database; which monitors water depth
 of wells in the High Plains Underground Water Conservation District. Managed well site equipment install, and continue to
 monitor daily function of the system. Well depth is recorded & displayed in real-time Database for all users, allowing reduction
 in field staff and savings to the District.
- Developed and wrote scripts for Interactive Well Map of the aquifer with Database available to staff and clients; providing complete drill down history, as well as current information on the wells.
- Digitized well records; 70,000 documents representing 65 years of aquifer management, allowing reduction in office staff and time savings by eliminating manual search of paper records.

EXPERIENCE

High Plains Underground Water Conservation District – Lubbock, Texas

2007 - Present

IT Manager

Determine, install, setup, manage and maintain IT-related equipment

Manage IT budget and expenditures; \$150K annual IT budget / \$3.5M total annual budget for the District

Develop and maintain information architecture

Train staff, and troubleshoot end-user problems

Implement and manage:

- Microsoft Server versions 2003 to current
- Microsoft Exchange versions 2010 to current
- Secure Firewall
- Backup procedures and processes; on premises, as well as offsite
- Remote office setup and support
- VoIP system
- Group Policies
- Website design and hosting

RIO Technical Services – Fort Worth, TX

2001 - 2007

Network Administrator/Computer Security

- Performed computer network administrative functions, including day-to-day operations of the internal network, infrastructure and software applications, as well as network security
- Assisted with integration of the networked system, ensuring compliance with in-house Software Quality Assurance guidelines
- Performed data queries, analytical data verification & correction; utilizing Integrated Environmental Database
- Provided IT troubleshooting (software and hardware issues) for the Fort Worth and Amarillo offices

EDUCATION

South Plains College

July 2015

Associate of Arts Degree, excelled in IT coursework

Tarleton State University

Fall 2001 – Spring 2003

Area of Study, Computer Information Systems

CONFERENCES AND CERTIFICATES

ESRI (Environmental Systems Research Institute) International User's Conference, San Diego, CA

Annually, July 2010 – 2018

Geographic Information System (GIS) software and geodatabase management applications

Open Meetings Act and Public Information Act December 2017

Certificate, State of Texas

Records Management Workshop September 2016

State & Local Records Mgmt Division of the Texas State Library & Archives Commission

Introduction to ArcGIS_> I July 2007

ESRI Certificate, Texas Tech University

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES

Military Service, United States Army

Volunteer, provide IT services to community nonprofit including set up of Website, Network, WIFI and PCs

Volunteer, team member of the Texas Ramp Project